Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: World War II (miscellaneous), circa 1942 - 1945; 10 (Box 1564)
    - TOKYO RAIDERS REUNION ON FIRST ANNIVERSARY; AFRICA - Major General Jimmy Doolittle (third from left, front row) who led the air raid on Japan on April 18, 1942, and some of the men who flew with him, are drinking a champagne toast from coffee cups during a reunion in North Africa on the first anniversary of the flight. The party was held in an Arab's barn which had been turned into an Officer's Club. Left to right, front row, Major William Bower, Ravenna, [California?]; Major Travis Hoover, Arlington, California; Doolittle; Lieutenant Colonel Harvey Hinman, San Francisco; Captain Heston C. Daniel, Plaquemine, Louisiana. Back row, left to right - Captain Howard A. Sessler of Arlington, Massachusetts; Captain William R. Pound, Jr., Kent Homes, Virginia; Major Rodney R. Wilder of Taylor, Texas; Captain James M. Parker, Livingston, Texas; Major Charles R. Greening, Tacoma, Washington; Major Joseph Klein, Paradise, Texas; Captain Griffith P. William, San Diego, California; and Captain Thomas C. Griffin of Chicago (E-7-15-43), 1
    - Note: TOKYO RAIDERS REUNION ON FIRST ANNIVERSARY; AFRICA - Major General Jimmy Doolittle (third from left, front row) who led the air raid on Japan on April 18, 1942, and some of the men who flew with him, are drinking a champagne toast from coffee cups during a reunion in North Africa on the first anniversary of the flight. The party was held in an Arab's barn which had been turned into an Officer's Club. Left to right, front row, Major William Bower, Ravenna, [California?]; Major Travis Hoover, Arlington, California; Doolittle; Lieutenant Colonel Harvey Hinman, San Francisco; Captain Heston C. Daniel, Plaquemine, Louisiana. Back row, left to right - Captain Howard A. Sessler of Arlington, Massachusetts; Captain William R. Pound, Jr., Kent Homes, Virginia; Major Rodney R. Wilder of Taylor, Texas; Captain James M. Parker, Livingston, Texas; Major Charles R. Greening, Tacoma, Washington; Major Joseph Klein, Paradise, Texas; Captain Griffith P. William, San Diego, California; and Captain Thomas C. Griffin of Chicago (E-7-15-43), 2
    - Rear Admiral C. E. Rosendahl, USN, 3
    - Verso: Rear Admiral C. E. Rosendahl, USN, 3-verso
    - U.S.S. Minneapolis (CA-36) - Heavy Cruiser, 4
    - Verso: U.S.S. Minneapolis (CA-36) - Heavy Cruiser, 4-verso
    - THE MINNEAPOLIS COMES BACK FIGHTING Back in the battleline after the completion of a spectacular repair job, 5
    - Verso: THE MINNEAPOLIS COMES BACK FIGHTING Back in the battleline after the completion of a spectacular repair job, 5-verso
    - THE BATTLE OF THE SOLOMON ISLANDS, AUGUST, 1942 Another view of Tulagi Island. Upper right shows the smoke plume of burning supplies following the attack, 6
    - Verso: THE BATTLE OF THE SOLOMON ISLANDS, AUGUST, 1942 Another view of Tulagi Island. Upper right shows the smoke plume of burning supplies following the attack, 6-verso
    - Douglas A-26 Invader - Newest, fastest and deadliest attack bomber, the A-26 incorporates speed with tremendous offensive and defensive firepower. (All armament has been deleted from this photograph for reasons of national security.), 7
    - Note: Douglas A-26 Invader - Newest, fastest and deadliest attack bomber, the A-26 incorporates speed with tremendous offensive and defensive firepower. (All armament has been deleted from this photograph for reasons of national security.), 8
    - Officers in conference on Guadalcanal in the early days of the campaign, August 11, 1942, 9
    - Verso: Officers in conference on Guadalcanal in the early days of the campaign, August 11, 1942, 9-verso
    - BRITISH OFFICER SPEAKS WITH GUADALCANAL NATIVE Captain Clement, of the Royal British Army, speaks to a young native of the group befriended by the U.S. marines on Guadalcanal Island, 10
    - Verso: BRITISH OFFICER SPEAKS WITH GUADALCANAL NATIVE Captain Clement, of the Royal British Army, speaks to a young native of the group befriended by the U.S. marines on Guadalcanal Island, 10-verso
    - SOLOMON NATIVES Natives, such as pictured above, inhabit the Solomon Islands where American and Japanese forces are now fighting for control, 11
    - Verso: SOLOMON NATIVES Natives, such as pictured above, inhabit the Solomon Islands where American and Japanese forces are now fighting for control, 11-verso
  - Subject files: The World of Lowell Thomas, undated; 11 (Box 1564)
    - With the BBC in London, "The World of Lowell Thomas" television series, 1
    - Note: With the BBC in London, "The World of Lowell Thomas" television series, 2
  - Subject files: Harold Bell Wright, undated; 12 (Box 1564)
    - Caption: Harold Bell Wright and family at their home in Imperial Valley. The author of "The Winning of Barbara Worth", 1
  - Subject files: Francis Yeats-Brown, undated; 13 (Box 1564)
    - Major F. Yeats-Brown, 1
    - Verso: Major F. Yeats-Brown, 1-verso
  - Subject files: Miscellaneous photographs with Lowell Thomas [unidentified event], circa 1960s; 14 (Box 1564)
    - [Lowell Thomas, standing at center, Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas seated in front of him], 1
    - Verso: Photot Credit: Stowe-News Bureau-Photo Mt. Mansfield Company, Inc. Stowe, Vermont, 1-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas, standing at center, Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas seated in front of him], 2
    - Verso: Photot Credit: Stowe-News Bureau-Photo Mt. Mansfield Company, Inc. Stowe, Vermont, 2-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting at a table and a man talking], 3
    - Verso: Photot Credit: Stowe-News Bureau-Photo Mt. Mansfield Company, Inc. Stowe, Vermont, 3-verso
    - [Man with a guitar making a speech], 4
    - Verso: Photot Credit: Stowe-News Bureau-Photo Mt. Mansfield Company, Inc. Stowe, Vermont, 4-verso
    - [Man with a guitar making a speech], 5
    - Verso: Photot Credit: Stowe-News Bureau-Photo Mt. Mansfield Company, Inc. Stowe, Vermont, 5-verso
    - [glass labeled "Spruce Stowe"], [3 copies], 6
    - Verso: Photot Credit: Stowe-News Bureau-Photo Mt. Mansfield Company, Inc. Stowe, Vermont, 6-verso
  - Subject files: Miscellaneous photographs with Lowell Thomas [includes color photographs], undated; 15 (Box 1564)
    - ['er 'ighness and 'is 'ighness attended by their gentlemen in waiting], 1
    - Verso: 'er 'ighness and 'is 'ighness attended by their gentlemen in waiting, 1-verso
    - fun Joseph P. Robinson 1955 in Tokyo, 2
    - Verso: fun Joseph P. Robinson 1955 in Tokyo, 2-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with two men in the snow], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas pointing at something], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas and a bunch of men], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to a man on top of a mountain], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man standing outside], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking with a woman], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man writing], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas and two others outside], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with a man], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas standing at a podium], 12
    - My Illustrious friend the complex human that has no end to anything life has to offer - you cannot describe his anology of things it has no seed., 13
    - Note: My Illustrious friend the complex human that has no end to anything life has to offer - you cannot describe his anology of things it has no seed., 14
  - Subject files: Miscellaneous photographs [includes color photographs], 1917 - 1975; 16 (Box 1564)
    - "CHRISTUS" NOW A SOLDIER: CALLED TO COLORS BY BAVARIAN GOVERNMENT Anton Lang, the "Christus" of Oberammergau's Passion Play, has finally been called to the colors, according to, 1
    - Note: "CHRISTUS" NOW A SOLDIER: CALLED TO COLORS BY BAVARIAN GOVERNMENT Anton Lang, the "Christus" of Oberammergau's Passion Play, has finally been called to the colors, according to, 2
    - Anton Lang Passon Play of 1900 The Crucifiction, 3
    - Verso: Anton Lang Passon Play of 1900 The Crucifiction, 3-verso
    - Caption: To Lowell Thomas. Rex Ingram (Telonet Haut Atlas 1931), 4
    - Caption: [illegible]; Verso: Mr Thomas- When the photographer too the flash I came near dropping the ball - thought camera shot at me - no there were no more pictures taken that year, 5
    - Verso: Mr Thomas- When the photographer too the flash I came near dropping the ball - thought camera shot at me - no there were no more pictures taken that year, 5-verso
    - Some of the "thousands and tens fo thousands of buckets" which were lost in the fire, 6
    - Note: Some of the "thousands and tens fo thousands of buckets" which were lost in the fire, 7
    - Caption: Dear Lowell, Thank you for giving me so many years of your life through radio. My Deepest Esteem, Herb, 8
    - Note: [5 letters between Lowell Thomas and Herb (an author)], [PDF], 9
    - [Man and a dog standing next to a waterfall], 10
    - Helen racing a 30'fer[?], 11
    - Verso: Helen racing a 30'fer[?], 11-verso
    - Jimmy + Chris Frazer 13 years, 20 years - 1963, 12
    - Verso: Jimmy + Chris Frazer 13 years, 20 years - 1963, 12-verso
    - Caption: X-15 Record Altitude Flight April 30, 1962, 13
  - Subject files: Miscellaneous photographs [includes color photographs], undated; 17 (Box 1564)
    - [Portrait of a woman], 1
    - [Aerial view of an estate], 2
    - ["George Foster Peabody Lover of Men"], 3
    - [Two children], 4
    - [Front door of a house in the woods], 5
    - [Three friends walking], 6
    - Portrait of a man], 7
    - [Crest with foxes], 8
    - [Person standing with an umbrella], 9
    - My wife and my dog - the wife has the beads on. Old stuff. What?, 10
    - Verso: My wife and my dog - the wife has the beads on. Old stuff. What?, 10-verso
    - Playing horse [house?], 11
    - Verso: Playing horse [house?], 11-verso
    - [Portrait of a man], 12
    - [A man with goggles], 13
    - From a painting by Joseph Mangulies, 14
    - Verso: From a painting by Joseph Mangulies, 14-verso
    - Taken at Waikiki Beach, T.H., 15
    - Verso: Taken at Waikiki Beach, T.H., 15-verso
    - [Various portraits of a couple], 16
    - [Portraits of a couple], 17
    - [Portraits of a couple], 18
    - Lowell Thomas Camera Team, Jerry + Hilu Feil Stone Age Man, 19
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas Camera Team, Jerry + Hilu Feil Stone Age Man, 19-verso
    - [A group of people standing in front of an ornate building], 20
    - [Someone swimming by a waterfall], 21
    - [Portrait of a woman], 22
    - [A ship at sea], 23
    - [A volcano in the background], 24
    - And so here I come to thank you with all my heart for your very good wishes! Most appreciatively yours, [signed] [illegible], 25
    - Verso: And so here I come to thank you with all my heart for your very good wishes! Most appreciatively yours, [signed] [illegible], 25-verso
    - [A giant organ and chior], 26
    - [Aerial view of a town], 27
    - [People in the snow], 28
    - [People skiing down a hill], 29
    - [People carrying their skiis], 30
    - [Three men sitting outside], 31
    - [People skiing on a frozen pond], 32
    - [Men carrying their skiis], 33
    - [Men skiing down a hill in the woods], 34
    - [A group of men standing by a car], 35
    - [A man drinking from a little waterfall], 36
    - [A group of men outside], 37
    - [A line of people walking through the forest], 38
    - [A group of men preparing a fire (?)], 39
    - [People skiing down a hill in the woods], 40
    - [Portrait of a woman sailing], 41
    - [Snow-capped mountains], 42
    - [Man and woman standing outside a house], 43
    - [Woman holding a baby], 44
    - The sun shows a new face when viewed from a Naval Research Laboratory rocket 123 miles high. This unusual photo--a "first"--presents the sun as recorded in detail in the extreme ultraviolet region of the spectrum. This is one in a series of rocket astronomy experiments being conducted by the Naval Research Laboratory under the auspices of the International Geophysical Year. (Photo taken on 13 March 1959). (Note: the large bright areas at the edge of the disc shoudl be on the viewer's right)., 45
    - Note: The sun shows a new face when viewed from a Naval Research Laboratory rocket 123 miles high. This unusual photo--a "first"--presents the sun as recorded in detail in the extreme ultraviolet region of the spectrum. This is one in a series of rocket astronomy experiments being conducted by the Naval Research Laboratory under the auspices of the International Geophysical Year. (Photo taken on 13 March 1959). (Note: the large bright areas at the edge of the disc shoudl be on the viewer's right)., 46
  - Subject files: Miscellaneous photographs [includes color photographs], undated; 18 (Box 1564)
    - Caption: To Fran + Lowell from an aging slugger and a new rookie!, 1
    - [Portrait of a woman], 2
    - Garst Museum, 3
    - Verso: Garst Museum, 3-verso
    - [Portrait of a baby], 4
    - [A man and a woman looking Lowell Thomas's book], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas travel brochures], 6
    - [A man getting into a helicoptor], 7
    - [Portrait of a woman], 8
    - [An indoor swimming pool], 9
    - [Bohemian Grove], 10
    - [semi-legible] Betty Fox, 11
    - Verso: [semi-legible] Betty Fox, 11-verso
    - [Soldiers raising the American flag], 12
    - [Man jumping over a river], 13
  Box 1565
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: ROLL 1 - 35 millimeter roll of contact prints, circa 1930s; 1 (Box 1565)
    - First section of ROLL 1 [Hammersley Hill, New York: House and grounds (images 1-9); church [Christ Church?] (images 10-12); Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 13); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 14-15); Lowell Thomas (image 16); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 17-28)], 1
    - Second section of ROLL 1 [Hammersley Hill, New York: House and grounds (images 1-9); church [Christ Church?] (images 10-12); Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 13); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 14-15); Lowell Thomas (image 16); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 17-28)], 2
    - Third section of ROLL 1 [Hammersley Hill, New York: House and grounds (images 1-9); church [Christ Church?] (images 10-12); Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 13); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 14-15); Lowell Thomas (image 16); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 17-28)], 3
    - Forth section of ROLL 1 [Hammersley Hill, New York: House and grounds (images 1-9); church [Christ Church?] (images 10-12); Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 13); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 14-15); Lowell Thomas (image 16); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 17-28)], 4
    - Fifth section of ROLL 1 [Hammersley Hill, New York: House and grounds (images 1-9); church [Christ Church?] (images 10-12); Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 13); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 14-15); Lowell Thomas (image 16); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 17-28)], 5
    - Sixth section of ROLL 1 [Hammersley Hill, New York: House and grounds (images 1-9); church [Christ Church?] (images 10-12); Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 13); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 14-15); Lowell Thomas (image 16); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 17-28)], 6
  - Subject files: ROLL 2 - 35 millimeter roll of contact prints, circa 1940s; 2 (Box 1565)
    - First section of ROLL 2 [Lowell Thomas, Jr. in uniform (images 1-6); Lowell Thomas (image7-8); winter scene (images 9-10); Lowell Thomas (images 11-13)], 1
    - Second section of ROLL 2 [Lowell Thomas, Jr. in uniform (images 1-6); Lowell Thomas (image7-8); winter scene (images 9-10); Lowell Thomas (images 11-13)], 2
    - Third section of ROLL 2 [Lowell Thomas, Jr. in uniform (images 1-6); Lowell Thomas (image7-8); winter scene (images 9-10); Lowell Thomas (images 11-13)], 3
  - Subject files: ROLL 3 - 35 millimeter roll of contact prints, circa 1940s; 3 (Box 1565)
    - First section of ROLL 3 [Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. in uniform (images 1-5); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 6-10); Lowell Thomas (image 11); Lowell Thomas and Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 12); Lowell Thomas, Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas, Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 13-14)], 1
    - Second section of ROLL 3 [Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. in uniform (images 1-5); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 6-10); Lowell Thomas (image 11); Lowell Thomas and Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 12); Lowell Thomas, Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas, Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 13-14)], 2
    - Third section of ROLL 3 [Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. in uniform (images 1-5); Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 6-10); Lowell Thomas (image 11); Lowell Thomas and Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 12); Lowell Thomas, Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas, Lowell Thomas, Jr. (images 13-14)], 3
  - Subject files: ROLL 4 - 35 millimeter roll of contact prints, undated; 4 (Box 1565)
    - First section of ROLL 4 [ski scenes: Lowell Thomas (images 4, 19-20, 23-24, 26, 28); Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 21)], 1
    - Second section of ROLL 4 [ski scenes: Lowell Thomas (images 4, 19-20, 23-24, 26, 28); Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 21)], 2
    - Third section of ROLL 4 [ski scenes: Lowell Thomas (images 4, 19-20, 23-24, 26, 28); Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 21)], 3
    - Forth section of ROLL 4 [ski scenes: Lowell Thomas (images 4, 19-20, 23-24, 26, 28); Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 21)], 4
    - Fifth section of ROLL 4 [ski scenes: Lowell Thomas (images 4, 19-20, 23-24, 26, 28); Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 21)], 5
    - Sixth section of ROLL 4 [ski scenes: Lowell Thomas (images 4, 19-20, 23-24, 26, 28); Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 21)], 6
    - Seventh section of ROLL 4 [ski scenes: Lowell Thomas (images 4, 19-20, 23-24, 26, 28); Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas (image 21)], 7
  - Subject files: ROLL 5 - 35 millimeter roll of contact prints, undated; 5 (Box 1565)
    - First section of ROLL 5 [ski scenes], 1
    - Second section of ROLL 5 [ski scenes], 2
    - Third section of ROLL 5 [ski scenes], 3
    - Forth section of ROLL 5 [ski scenes], 4
    - Fifth section of ROLL 5 [ski scenes], 5
    - Sixth section of ROLL 5 [ski scenes], 6
    - Seventh section of ROLL 5 [ski scenes], 7